[Jang Siyul grunting]
[exhales]
[♪ melancholy music playing]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[exhales]
The Murky Stream
EIGHT. TO LIVE OR TO DIE
[Lee Dolgae] Open it.
[lock clacking]
You bastard.
You attack in plain sight?
I only did it to grant the wish of a man
who was asking for death himself.
I would like you to tell me
why I'm still being kept here.
You're still holding your head up high
which tells me you don't understand.
This is much more serious
than you can imagine.
Have I not already explained?
He was the first to attack with his knife.
Not me.
[sighs]
So what?
You have my life to use at your disposal.
Keep me alive if you want to.
If I'm not useful, get rid of me.
You know that I am here
to follow your orders, My Lord.
How nice.
You are a very well-mannered person.
Then swear to me.
Will you turn into the beast I wield
without restraint?
Bark if I tell you to bark?
Bite when I command you to kill?
I'm willing to do whatever you ask of me.
[♪ tense music playing]
Are you now?
Yes, I am.
I'm willing to throw myself in a fire
if that's what you require of me.
[laughing]
[chuckles softly]
[continues laughing]
[♪ music continues playing]
[Captain Park clears throat, exhales]
Wang Hae was set free.
Who ordered his release?
Is there a reason for your concern?
That criminal wasn't even questioned yet.
So why was he released?
I made my decision
after reviewing the case thoroughly.
And that is that.
Malbok was the one who started the fight
from what I've heard.
Wang Hae was defending himself
against the man who tried to kill him.
How can we charge him for doing that?
If anyone is guilty,
it should be the boy who started it.
They say he went out of his way
to find and kill that boy.
-Is that not so?
-[winces]
Those are the words of mere bandits.
How could you believe
everything they say, huh?
[Jung Chun] We don't know.
That is why we must conduct
an investigation.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[Lee Dolgae exhales]
You know what I think?
-I think you're suspicious.
-What's that supposed to mean?
Why are you making such a fuss?
This case is clearly important to you.
Look here, Officer Jung.
I heard an interesting rumor.
On your first day, you had a meeting
with a scum of a man they call Jang,
by your choosing.
[laughs exultantly]
How can we guarantee a fair investigation,
when we have a dishonest officer like you
in charge, right?
[chuckling] Absolute nonsense. Hilarious!
[laughs]
Don't you agree, Captain Park?
-Yes.
-[laughing]
[scoffs]
Keep laughing.
Laugh all you want.
[laughs exultantly]
[continues laughing]
[Jageun Ae] Jungbok.
Jungbok.
You really must eat something now.
All right.
[door opens]
Is Jungbok okay?
He doesn't feel like eating. [sighs]
[sighs]
Hey, Boss. Did you hear what happened?
The Police Bureau decided to release
that Wang Hae bastard.
Poor Malbok.
We need to take revenge for him.
You idiots still haven't learned
your damn lesson.
Tell me. How many thumbs or forefingers
came to Malbok's funeral?
Not a single one!
Why?
In times of misfortune,
all bandits just walk away.
Why do you think
everyone's tiptoeing around
as if they're scared to make noise?
Getting on Wang Hae's bad side
means they'll disappear without a trace.
And you want to take revenge?
Just look at the state of the world
that we live in.
[sniffles]
[Gaechun] Boss, no.
That man murdered our brother...
[sniffles]
and you want us to bow to him? Really?
What the hell do you take me for, bastard?
[sighs]
Where did Siyul go?
He was over at the dock.
He's sitting at the riverbank now.
All day long,
he's been staring out at the water.
-He won't answer anyone who calls.
-[exhales]
[crying]
Our little Malbok was so kind.
I hope he went to a good place
even though he was a bandit.
-[cries]
-[exhales]
Don't be so stupid!
Why would you even say some...
something like that?
[Gaechun continues crying]
It's not like
he has any other place to go.
[both crying]
Be quiet and eat your damn meal!
It's bad luck to talk about the dead
when you're eating.
[clattering]
Why do you raise your voice
while we're eating dinner?
I'm trying to eat.
Keep eating.
Eat. You too, Gaechun.
-Eat up.
-[Walwal sniffles]
[♪ somber music playing]
You seem familiar.
I think it's the look in your eyes.
[Jang Siyul] I swear... I will kill you.
[Wang Hae grunting]
[♪ music continues playing]
[footsteps approaching]
[Choi Jeongyeop] Hello, My Lord.
[Yu Taeseok] You may enter.
Don't worry. I assure you
you can trust this man.
Introduce yourself.
I am Choi Jeongyeop.
Assistant Officer Jung Chun
of the Police Bureau.
[exhales]
So all of these pieces here,
this is the map?
The map will be completed soon,
and we will finally see the full picture.
This is truly amazing.
Major and minor roads crossing each other.
It shows the locations of provinces,
townships,
beacons, and even all the fortresses.
[man breathing heavily]
[Jung Chun] I've never seen a map
so detailed and elaborate.
It's unbelievable.
And really, I owe it all to this man here.
My Lord.
I had told my daughter,
that it could be a while
before our nation stands upright again.
Is that still what you think?
I'm no longer certain.
Now I am placing my hope in you.
Hope, you say?
My only wish... is that you and I
can use this map for a good cause.
If that is your wish, I'm glad to hear it.
We share the same ideas.
A map?
I saw a few painters working on it.
I'm sure that's what it was.
I saw it with my very own eyes.
This map showed all eight provinces
of Joseon?
You swear it?
I would never dare to lie to you.
I know that is what I saw.
I swear on my life.
[shudders]
You must do... exactly as I tell you to.
Yes.
[laughs]
Oh... It was a map?
Are you sure about that?
Multiple painters are staying there.
Everyone else is locked out.
No one can even approach the building.
I see! I had expected him to do this
for a while now.
It's been said that he who owns the roads
can also command the country.
And now maps are seen
as treasonous and forbidden.
This is an act of rebellion as I see it.
What could it be...
if not for treason?
My! It is! [laughs]
However, My Lord,
it's only a suspicion.
But it's true that a lot of people
still trust and follow
the Senior Guardian General.
Don't you think
that's actually better for us?
The commoners trust and follow him
as if he were king.
If that's not a traitor, then what is?
The Senior Guardian General
was an outstanding government official
and officer,
yet I never respected the General
at any point along his career.
Ultimately, human nature
is like a starving demon.
It's all disgusting and rotten.
It's total hypocrisy.
And do not forget.
His death is the only way
for you to survive.
By working tirelessly,
I'll bring to you evidence you require
to prove he's guilty of treason.
[laughs maliciously]
[Mudeok] Officer.
Who's there?
[Jung Chun sighs]
It's late out. Why are you here?
I came all this way...
because I need to ask you
to do me a favor.
What kind of favor?
[sighs]
JUNG CHUN
What?
How did you get your hands on this?
Siyul was never able to leave Mapo,
you see... [inhales]
all because of that letter.
Just tell me what's happening.
I am worried that right now,
Siyul is heading
straight into the belly of the beast.
Only you can put a stop to him, My Lord.
Siyul needs to leave Mapo
for his own good.
So convince him to go.
[♪ melancholy music playing]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[inhales]
[panting]
[exhales, panting]
You have my condolences.
I heard you cherished the boy
like he was a brother.
Are you going to be okay?
You seem determined not to say anything.
[exhales]
A man named Mudeok, he gave this to me.
Siyul, why didn't you tell me?
I had never expected that
my letter would put you in this situation.
Are you really planning on
going through with this?
Chun.
I think you'd better go.
I don't wish to talk to anyone right now.
You can hold it against me if you want.
But I don't want you to get hurt.
Truly.
You needn't worry.
How could I fault you for that?
You do what you have to do.
And I'll do what I have to.
That's all there is.
[♪ music continues playing]
Please be careful.
[Mudeok] Where the hell have you been?
[Jang Siyul sighs]
[breathes deeply]
How are you?
You okay?
This letter...
Thank you.
You can bring it with you...
[inhales]
Go wherever you want.
You treat bandits as if we're snakes.
These days, I've been getting
really sick of seeing you.
If you want me to leave, I will.
But first...
I will give back
what I owe you before I do.
How thick in the head
could you possibly be, kid?
Pursuing revenge is a bad idea.
Wang Hae's not someone
you should mess with.
Whatever you say,
it won't make a difference to me.
I swear...
I will make him pay no matter what.
And then what?
Have you considered
the consequences at all?
After you cause a scene
and leave us all here?
Do you think we can survive on our own?
I'm beggin' you not to do anything
for our sakes and just go!
Sorry, but I can't.
You idiot!
So we'll be stuck
eating filthy rice again,
and it'll all be thanks to you?
Do you think I can't just kill you myself?
If I take this letter over
to the Police Bureau,
they wouldn't hesitate
to slice your tongue off with an axe!
I know.
Take my letter...
and do whatever you want with it.
And I will do what I have to do.
[Mudeok] You fucking bastard.
I don't even need this, asshole!
[sighs] What's wrong with kids these days?
[inhales, sighs] Whatever.
[chuckles softly]
[softly] Yes.
You did it.
[chuckling] You did it.
[Yu Taeseok] This is...
Extraordinary.
[chuckles in amazement]
[Lee Dolgae]
You've taught me to be patient.
To wait...
Until I know that
the fruit has been ripened.
Absolutely.
If you pick the fruit when it's not ripe,
you cannot enjoy the sweet flavor.
The time is upon us.
I think the fruit... is sweetest now.
Then the map is what you need to acquire.
If you have to cut his throat for it,
I don't care in the least.
No, that is exactly how it must be done.
Once you find where he's hiding,
I want you to tear him apart limb by limb
until nothing at all is left. [inhales]
Do you understand?
[exhales] Of course, My Lord.
Now, you are the Police Bureau's General.
[Lord Oh chuckles]
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
Officer Lee.
Bring them in.
It begins tonight.
Is that fear I sense?
No, sir.
I will follow your commands.
[♪ intense music playing]
[groans]
[screams, panicking]
[wails]
What is the matter?
[creaks]
[sighs] We may be in danger.
-What?
-[Yu Taeseok] This is my fault.
I should have seen this coming
and prepared us for it.
I was overjoyed by the map's completion,
and I let my guard down.
My Lord, please go now
while you're still able.
Secure the map quickly.
Now!
-[Choi Jeongyeop] Hurry!
-[painter] Yes!
[indistinct chatter]
Listen to me carefully.
[Choi Jeongyeop] Yes.
I'm entrusting the map to you.
What?
Can you deliver this to Lord Jo Yusu,
the Magistrate in Ganghwa?
My Lord!
I know you understand
how important this map is.
It could be the salvation of Joseon.
If it ends up in the hands
of the wrong people,
our whole nation could be at risk.
Joseon and its people
could face extinction.
The very future of Joseon...
rests with this map.
[♪ music continues playing]
I will do my best.
I appreciate it.
[grunting]
I will try to buy you some time.
Use the door up there.
[exhales]
Wait.
I need you to swear.
You mustn't leave a single trace
of the map behind, or let anyone take it.
No matter who might try and do so.
I need you to swear.
[exhales] I give you my word.
Now go, quickly.
[grunts] Take these.
-[painter] Go, go, go! [grunts]
-Stack them up, and block the entrance.
[Yu Taeseok grunts]
[♪ music continues playing]
[slams, creaks]
[grunting]
[thuds]
[painters whimper softly]
[painters whimper louder]
[men grunting, yelling]
[men continue grunting, yelling]
[yelling]
-[clattering]
-[painters groan]
You dare to break in here?
Sheath your swords.
Nice to make your acquaintance.
I am Wang Hae.
I've been told a man from the north
has taken over the docks
and is sowing chaos.
That man has to be you.
I am honored that you would recognize me.
Tell me.
Where is it that
you've hidden the map, My Lord?
What?
Now depending on my decision,
there's a good chance that you won't
make it outta here in one piece.
You dare threaten me?
I suggest you leave while you can.
[scoffs]
-[swords clashing]
-[men grunting, yelling]
[shudders]
[Wang Hae] Where is the map?
Speak.
If you don't answer me,
you will die like all your other friends.
[painter whimpers]
Don't kill me!
-[stuttering] It's the--
-Do not speak.
[screams]
[scoffs]
Your swordsmanship
lives up to your reputation.
You are welcome to try me.
[in Manchu] Give him what he asks for.
-[screams, grunts]
-[swords clashing]
[screams]
[panting]
[screaming]
-[screams, grunts]
-[swords clashing]
[screams]
[exhales]
-[grunts]
-[swords clashing]
[♪ music continues playing]
-[screaming]
-[swords clashing]
[breathes heavily]
-[Acham yelling]
-[swords clashing]
[groans]
[yells]
[in Manchu] What are you doing?
You can't even handle an old man?
[yells]
-[grunting]
-[swords clashing]
[Choi Jeongyeop panting]
[clicking]
[♪ music continues playing]
-[grunting]
-[swords clashing]
[groans]
[panting, grunts softly]
[breathes heavily]
-[yells]
-[groans softly]
-[screams]
-[grunts]
[screaming]
-[yells]
-[groans]
[groans]
-[chokes]
-[screams]
[in Manchu] We must not kill him.
Don't ruin the job
with your personal emotions.
[breathing heavily]
[panting]
[in English] How did it go?
I'll take care of it.
No need to worry anymore, sir.
General.
[shudders softly]
[indistinct chatter in distance]
[pants]
Well, is it here?
We searched thoroughly.
[exhales] It's nowhere to be found.
My Lord.
They are barbarians.
As wild as animals.
I can't let this happen to you.
I don't want your life
to end up in these people's hands.
-So, where is the map hidden?
-[Wang Hae] My Lord.
He bit his tongue off
and is unable to speak.
[grunts, gurgles]
Shit.
[scoffs]
-[groans softly]
-You are the most frustrating
and pitiful excuse for a man.
[tuts]
[long inhale] See you in the next life.
[gags]
[gags softly]
[Jung Chun shudders]
My last gift to you.
Don't resent me for what I've done.
My Lord.
Choi Jeongyeop is not here.
I don't see him anywhere.
I know who Choi Jeongyeop is.
Isn't he the owner of Choi's guild?
[servant] Yes.
I noticed him here earlier,
but he has disappeared.
I know this man.
And I can tell you exactly where he lives.
[shudders]
[Lee Dolgae] Go!
Without the map, all of you are dead too.
You must find it at all costs.
[exhales]
Father.
[inhales] Stay quiet.
We must leave quickly now.
-What?
-Go to Daegwang Temple.
Remain there
with your brother for a while.
Monk Jingwan will help you.
It's the middle of the night.
There's no time to explain.
Where are the documents that I gave you?
[exhales softly]
They're in the flower-patterned closet.
Get them right now.
[sighs]
Wake up Seomseom and come to my quarters.
You must hurry.
[panting]
Sir, what-- What is going on?
I need to get to Ganghwa Island.
You mean right now?
What's the fastest way to get there?
The fastest way there is by boat,
but it's too dark.
Finding someone to take you
at this hour will not be easy.
[breathes deeply]
[pants] Father.
Here. These are
the farm deeds you requested.
Did you pack your things?
Yes. I packed only the essentials for now.
[breathes heavily]
Head straight down to the dock.
The price doesn't matter.
Just find the fastest boat
and wait for me there.
Yes, leave it to me.
Be quick. There is no time to waste.
I'll head to the dock and wait for you.
Chief Kang.
[inhales] You go on first and take this.
There are silver ingots
and a promissory note
for 2000 nyang issued by the guild.
They're as good as currency.
Use them when you need to.
[Choi Eun] What about you?
What is it that
you're going to do, Father?
Eun. You must be strong of heart
and mind from here on.
My Lord! My Lord!
I think some people jumped over the wall.
Who is it? What aren't you telling me?
-You have to go right now. Get up.
-What?
Just do what I tell you to do.
Every second matters.
I will meet you at Daegwang Temple soon.
Seomseom, take good care of Eun.
Yes, My Lord.
You need to leave now. We're out of time.
Please...
promise you'll be there.
I need you to go now.
[♪ suspenseful music playing]
[in Manchu] You, go inside.
Scatter and find him.
[panting]
[Eun shudders softly]
[sniffs]
[grunting softly]
[in Manchu] The room is empty.
Search the house.
The candle is still burning.
He probably hasn't escaped yet.
Choi Jeongyeop. He must have the map.
[♪ music continues playing]
[Choi Jeongyeop panting]
[Yu Taeseok] I know you understand
how important this map is.
If it ends up in the hands
of the wrong people,
our whole nation could be at risk.
Joseon and its people
could face extinction.
The very future of Joseon
rests with this map.
[sighs]
[Choi Eun pants]
[♪ music continues playing]
[both scream, shudder]
[crackling]
[in English] Tell me where your father is.
[breathes heavily]
[Wang Hae] It's time for you to die.
You'll meet your father in the next life.
[shudders softly]
-[screams]
-[yelling]
[Acham grunts]
[gasps]
[Jung Chun breathing heavily]
Are you all right?
Assistant Officer.
Are you that eager
to meet a painful death?
Step aside, we can let you walk away.
Shut your mouth.
Let's find out
if you're more than just hollow threats.
[♪ intense music playing]
[in Manchu] Why is every Joseon person
so foolish?
Slay him.
[screams]
-[swords clashing]
-[both grunting]
[in English] Hurry and go.
If you get stuck,
look for the forefinger in Mapo.
He'll be able to help.
-[gasps]
-[Seomseom] My lady.
-[in Manchu] Catch that wench!
-[Jung Chun] Run!
-[yells]
-[grunting]
[swords clashing]
[grunting]
[♪ music continues playing]
[in Manchu] Kill him first!
[screams]
[♪ music intensifies]
[Wang Hae, Jung Chun scream, grunt]
[all scream, grunt]
[♪ music intensifies]
-[screams]
-[all grunting]
[swords clashing]
[screams]
[grunts, groans]
[grunts]
[coughs]
[Jung Chun breathing heavily]
[screaming]
[woman groans, gasps]
[both screaming]
[gulps]
[shudders]
[groans]
[Jung Chun shudders]
[in English] Make sure to watch carefully
when you get to the afterlife.
You'll see who ends up taking control...
[screams] of this rotten country!
[gulps]
[breathing heavily]
[in Manchu] General. There's smoke
coming from the storage room.
[Choi Eun panting]
-My lady. [grunts]
-[Choi Eun panting]
Father?
[in Manchu] This way.
[flames sizzling]
Choi Jeongyeop is inside.
Break the door!
[grunting]
[Acham screams]
[Acham coughing]
That is not a map.
[screaming]
[breath trembling]
[♪ melancholy music playing]
[♪ music continues playing]